Mauricio Vásquez Bernal

Software Engineer Research Assistant Polytechnic University of Turin



Aug 31, 1991



mauriciovasquezbernal@gmail.com



mauriciovasquezbernal.github.io



Medellín - Colombia

Languages

Spanish Italian





Skills -

Programming Languages

С C++ Go Python Java • • • •

Computer Networks

eBPF and XDP TCP/IP SDN and NFV

Virtualization

KVM/QEMU Open vSwitch Docker & LXC

• • •

0 0 0

Kubernetes **OpenStack**

Software Development

Git **Open Source**

Soft Skills -

GDB

Problem Solving Self-Motivation Communication **Teamwork**

Profile

Young software engineer with 3+ years of experience in software development. I am a proactive team member, very motivated and enthusiast about new life challenges. I am one of the main developers of Polycube, an open source framework for developing virtual network functions with eBPF and XDP. I play nicely with open source development, I have contributed to different projects like Linux kernel, BPF Compiler Collection (BCC), Open vSwitch (OVS) and Data Plane Development Kit (DPDK).

Experience

Feb 2016 -Present

Research Assistant

Polytechnic University of Turin

• Developing of polycube, an open source framework to build fast and lightweight virtual network functions witheBPF

- Developing of high-performance virtual network functions with eBPF and XDP
- Contributing to open source projects like Linux kernel and BCC

Feb 2015 -May 2017

Consultant

Nebbiolo Technologies

Sep 2016 -

Consultant

• Implementing high performant virtual network functions with eBPF Plumgrid (Acquired by VMware)

Jan 2017

• Developing iovisor-ovn, an eBPF datapath for Open Virtual Net-

working (OVN)

Jan 2015 -Aug 2016

Research Assistant

Polytechnic University of Turin

- Developing of a high-performance communication channel for inter-VM communication in Open vSwitch
- Contributing to open source projects like Open vSwitch (OvS) and Dataplane Development Kit (DPDK)
- Participating in the Unify European Project

Education

2013 – 2015 Master in Computer Engineering Polytechnic University of Turin 2009 - 2013 Bachelor in Electronic Engineering University of Antioquia

Projects

Polycube

github.com/polycube-network/polycube

Polycube is an open source framework for developing fast and lightweight network functions using eBPF and XDP.

IOVisor-ovn

github.com/iovisor/iovisor-ovn

IOVisor-ovn is an eBPF based datapath for the Open Virtual Networking project. It provides a virtual networking solution for virtual machines in environments like Open Stack.

Squadra Corse Polito

facebook.com/pg/SCPolito

Squadra Corse is a student racing team from Polytechnic University of Turin. Each year the team design, build and test an electric car to compete against teams from other universities all around the world. I was in charge of developing the telemetry and datalogging systems.

Publications

Jun 2018 Creating Complex Network Services with eBPF: Experience and **Lessons Learned HSPR** Oct 2018 Transparent Optimization of Inter-Virtual Network Function Communication in Open vSwitch

A Transparent Highway for inter-Virtual Network Function Com-Aug 2016

munication with Open vSwitch

SIGCOMM